<rss version='2.0'>
  <channel>
    <title>Waves from Pegovka Observatory</title>
    <link>https://pegovka.space/</link>
    <description>Astronomer Ivan Zaytsev personal blog</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 13:02:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>pegovka.space</generator>
    
    <image>
    <url>https://pegovka.space/og-image.png</url>
    <title>Waves from Pegovka Observatory</title>
    <link>https://pegovka.space/</link>
    <width>100</width>
    <height>100</height>
    </image>

    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1025</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 13:02:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>One Small Step for Scientists and Engineers, a Giant Leap for Mankind</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1025</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <span><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j7kVUaZCcMU" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0"></iframe></span><p> Hi.</p><p>Yesterday I posted a video asking for your help deciphering a strange radio signal from space. Thanks to my friends from the <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/icfpcontest2020/status/1278965948461056000">ICFP Contest</a>, it was a tremendous success.</p><p>With help from enthusiasts all over the world we were able to make <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/radio-transmission-recording.html">great progress</a> in understanding the message. Thank you very much to all the participants!</p><p>First of all, we understand that the signal is probably a sequence of frequency-encoded ones and zeroes. When arranged into a particular two-dimensional grid they look like a picture that makes sense to a human eye!</p><p><img alt="transmission signal in 2d" src="https://pegovka.space/radio-transmission-2d.png"></p><p>Second, we have some theories on how to interpret this picture. It looks like a binary encoding of numbers from 1 to 8 that follows a regular pattern that can be extended further to construct any natural number. However, we don’t have any hard data to support our construction…</p><p><img alt="how to encode numbers" src="https://pegovka.space/numbers-encoding4.png"></p><p>Okay, here is the exciting part! I just got a second message! I’m going to apply the code I got from you yesterday to convert this second signal into a picture. I’ll post this picture to <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/message2.html">a separate page</a> in our documentation so we can collaborate on the explanation.</p><p>So excited! Can’t wait to <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/xvMJbas">work with you</a> once again!</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1024</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 07:10:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>A Personal Appeal to Scientists and Engineers From All Over the World</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[<span><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EjL-5EuQeCU" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0"></iframe></span><p> Hello.</p><p>My name is Ivan Zaitsev. I'm a staff astronomer at Pegovka observatory in the Urals region of Russia.</p><p>Several days ago we have been monitoring radio signals from a small region of sky around <a target="_blank" href="http://simbad.u-strasbg.fr/simbad/sim-id?Ident=HD+190360">HD 190360</a> for our exoplanet research purposes. We have registered a peculiar radio transmission which cannot be attributed to any natural source in this area.</p><p>We tried to analyze and decode this message. But we don't have any trained deciphering specialists here on site, and we don't have appropriate software to analyze this message. We have made very little progress so far.</p><p>I believe that decoding this message can lead to a major breakthrough in our understanding of the Universe. I believe that science should be a joint effort. Together we can crack this problem much faster that any single research group.</p><p>That's why I decided to publish a <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/_downloads/822b494d13eb35a97f159e041a004fa9/radio-transmission-recording.wav">recording of this message</a> and create a <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/radio-transmission-recording.html">special documentation page</a> to collaborate on the explanation.</p><p>If you have any idea at all on how to decode and explain the message, please send a Pull Request to the <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/zaitsev85/message-from-space/blob/master/source/radio-transmission-recording.rst">appropriate page</a>! We cannot move forward without this!</p><p>Sincerely,
                            Ivan Zaitsev</p><p>P.S. Don't hesitate to join my personal <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/xvMJbas">chat server</a> to combine our efforts in the spirit of open scientific collaboration.</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1023</guid>
      <pubDate>29 Jun 2015 13:04:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>No Title</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1023</link>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img alt="flowers" src="https://pegovka.space/flowers.jpeg"></p><p>Petunias look great this year!</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/0</guid>
      <pubDate>20 Mar 2008 21:14:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/0</link>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Dear diary,</p><p>I don't know why I'm here. Maybe one day I'll need a place for amazing
       news about space. So I'll try to blog something interesting once in a while.</p>]]></description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
