<rss version='2.0'>
  <channel>
    <title>Waves from Pegovka Observatory</title>
    <link>https://pegovka.space/</link>
    <description>Astronomer Ivan Zaytsev personal blog</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2020 13:00:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>pegovka.space</generator>
    
    <image>
    <url>https://pegovka.space/og-image.png</url>
    <title>Waves from Pegovka Observatory</title>
    <link>https://pegovka.space/</link>
    <width>100</width>
    <height>100</height>
    </image>

    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1029</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2020 13:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>The Origin Is Still Unknown</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1029</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <p>We’ve checked the specifications of each piece of our radio equipment and analyzed the archives of our observations for the past five years. We found nothing that would support our suspicion of a terrestrial origin of the signal.</p><p>We’ve also consulted with several computer security specialists and checked the raw telescope data to rule out malicious hacker activity. So far our investigation results support the extraterrestrial origin theory.</p><p>Our research group will continue the investigation. Meanwhile, <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/xvMJbas">join us</a> in dechipering <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/message6.html">today’s message</a>.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1028</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 21:32:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>What Do We Know So Far?</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1028</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <p>We’ve got five radio transmissions while monitoring a region of sky around HD 190360. We’re not sure of the source, but we strongly suspect that they are not coming from a star system 52 lightyears away.</p><p>We suspect that humans are the intended recipients of these messages because the transmissions are so precisely synchronized with the rotation of our planet. So far each message was received around 12:45 UTC every day, except for the first one.</p><p>The messages are frequency-encoded bit sequences that align neatly into 2D rectangles suggested by a frame. We have some theories on how to interpret them. Most of the theories are speculative until we get more information.</p><p>The first two messages introduce glyphs used to denote the natural numbers. The third message extends this construction to the negative numbers. The fourth message probably introduces the equality sign. The fifth message probably introduces the successor (+1) function for numbers and the application operator.</p><p>Thanks to our <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/xvMJbas">Discord chat</a> participants, we have nice tooling that allows us to render images from a radio transmission and to annotate these images with known glyph interpretations:</p><p><img alt="annotated image from day 5" src="https://pegovka.space/images/message5-annotated-full.svg"></p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1027</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 13:03:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>Not a Distant Planet?</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1027</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <p>Today I’ve got good news and also somewhat worrying news for you.</p><p>First, there is a transmission. Posted to <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/message4.html">docs</a>, as always. Some new glyphs for you to decipher.</p><p>Second, I think we have something to worry about. There is a strong suspicion among my colleagues that this signal comes not from a distant planet at all. We will thoroughly investigate this and try to eliminate possible terrestrial and low-orbit sources of this signal. I’ll get back to you with more details later.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1026</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 13:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>Once Is Luck, Twice Is Coincidence, Three Times Is a Pattern</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1026</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <p>Not entirely unexpected, we got a third message today. I’ve already posted it to our <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/message3.html">documentation page</a>. Can somebody take a look?</p><p>Feels like this is not the last one. What’s weird: we get these transmissions precisely at the same time each day, <strong>around 12:45 UTC</strong>. It’s almost like whatever sends them knows about us, and our planet is the intended target of these messages. Otherwise, why would timing of these messages be synchronized to the rotation of our planet?</p><p>I’ll be monitoring our radiotelescope carefully during the same time window tomorrow, expecting more answers from the Universe.</p><p>Join me in our <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/xvMJbas">Discord chat</a> to share your ideas and interpretations!</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1025</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 13:02:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>One Small Step for Scientists and Engineers, a Giant Leap for Mankind</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1025</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <span><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j7kVUaZCcMU" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0"></iframe></span><p> Hi.</p><p>Yesterday I posted a video asking for your help deciphering a strange radio signal from space. Thanks to my friends from the <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/icfpcontest2020/status/1278965948461056000">ICFP Contest</a>, it was a tremendous success.</p><p>With help from enthusiasts all over the world we were able to make <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/radio-transmission-recording.html">great progress</a> in understanding the message. Thank you very much to all the participants!</p><p>First of all, we understand that the signal is probably a sequence of frequency-encoded ones and zeroes. When arranged into a particular two-dimensional grid they look like a picture that makes sense to a human eye!</p><p><img alt="transmission signal in 2d" src="https://pegovka.space/images/radio-transmission-2d.png"></p><p>Second, we have some theories on how to interpret this picture. It looks like a binary encoding of numbers from 1 to 8 that follows a regular pattern that can be extended further to construct any natural number. However, we don’t have any hard data to support our construction…</p><p><img alt="how to encode numbers" src="https://pegovka.space/images/numbers-encoding4.png"></p><p>Okay, here is the exciting part! I just got a second message! I’m going to apply the code I got from you yesterday to convert this second signal into a picture. I’ll post this picture to <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/message2.html">a separate page</a> in our documentation so we can collaborate on the explanation.</p><p>So excited! Can’t wait to <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/xvMJbas">work with you</a> once again!</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1024</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 07:10:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>A Personal Appeal to Scientists and Engineers From All Over the World</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[<span><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EjL-5EuQeCU" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0"></iframe></span><p> Hello.</p><p>My name is Ivan Zaitsev. I'm a staff astronomer at Pegovka observatory in the Urals region of Russia.</p><p>Several days ago we have been monitoring radio signals from a small region of sky around <a target="_blank" href="http://simbad.u-strasbg.fr/simbad/sim-id?Ident=HD+190360">HD 190360</a> for our exoplanet research purposes. We have registered a peculiar radio transmission which cannot be attributed to any natural source in this area.</p><p>We tried to analyze and decode this message. But we don't have any trained deciphering specialists here on site, and we don't have appropriate software to analyze this message. We have made very little progress so far.</p><p>I believe that decoding this message can lead to a major breakthrough in our understanding of the Universe. I believe that science should be a joint effort. Together we can crack this problem much faster that any single research group.</p><p>That's why I decided to publish a <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/_downloads/822b494d13eb35a97f159e041a004fa9/radio-transmission-recording.wav">recording of this message</a> and create a <a target="_blank" href="https://message-from-space.readthedocs.io/en/latest/radio-transmission-recording.html">special documentation page</a> to collaborate on the explanation.</p><p>If you have any idea at all on how to decode and explain the message, please send a Pull Request to the <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/zaitsev85/message-from-space/blob/master/source/radio-transmission-recording.rst">appropriate page</a>! We cannot move forward without this!</p><p>Sincerely,
                            Ivan Zaitsev</p><p>P.S. Don't hesitate to join my personal <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/xvMJbas">chat server</a> to combine our efforts in the spirit of open scientific collaboration.</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1023</guid>
      <pubDate>29 Jun 2015 13:04:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>No Title</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/1023</link>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img alt="flowers" src="https://pegovka.space/images/flowers.jpeg"></p><p>Petunias look great this year!</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://pegovka.space/#/post/0</guid>
      <pubDate>20 Mar 2008 21:14:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <author>Ivan Zaitsev</author><link>https://pegovka.space/#/post/0</link>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Dear diary,</p><p>I don't know why I'm here. Maybe one day I'll need a place for amazing
       news about space. So I'll try to blog something interesting once in a while.</p>]]></description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
